Register of the UFA motion picture newsreels
Hoover Institution Archives
- Motion Picture Films, 1939-1945 (Film shelf)
  - UFA, Inland, 1939-1945
    - Reel 543
      1. Norway, composer Christian Sinding; 2. Oslo, Norwegian unemployed leave for Germany for work; 3. Poland, German soldiers help rebuild farms; 4. Tunnel for train being reopened; 5. Paris, Franz Lehar conducts orchestra; 6. Kärnten, Austria, Hitler Youth leaders meet; 7. Dr. Dietrich at Academy for European Culture; 8. Hanover, Rudolf Hess and new Gauleiter at city hall; 9. Berlin, Adrian Mussen addresses Dutch residences; 10. Berlin, Gen. Yamashita presents von Brauchitsch with samurai katana; 11. Production of helmets; 12. Storm Troops practice maneuvers in snow; 13. Crew of new "Kondor" bomber; 14. Malta, German and Italian planes on bombing run; 15. S. Atlantic, German U-Boat crew on patrol.
    - Reel 544
      1. Berlin, Hitler, Frick, funeral of Franz Gurtner; 2. Berlin, Hitler meets with Hungarian official at Riechchancellary; 3. Berlin, Hitler and Gen. Yamashita meet together; 4. Jan. 30, Berlin, Sport Palace, Hitler gives speech on 8th anniversary of Third Reich.
      4. (cont.), Hitler, Goebbels, Hess, Ley, Rosenberg, Hitler speaks to group; 5. Skiing competition; 6. Poland, ship caught in ice; 7. Copenhagen, German troops march through city to relieve guards; 8. Channel coast, heavy artillery shells Dover; 9. Pilot of recon plane lands; 10. Luftwaffe planes take off and bomb British ships; 11. Crews of light cruiser doing various things on deck.
    - Reel 545
      1. Budapest, state funeral for Hungarian; 2. Hitler, Kurusu, farewell visit to Hitler; 3. Japan, German Shepherd dogs with Japanese troops on maneuvers; 4. Oslo, Axmann inspects Hitler Youth unit; 5. Oslo, civilians and soldiers leave by train for winter sports.
      6. Baron von Neurath, Hierl observe parade; 7. Prague, Dr. Ley, concert of military music; 8. Poland, Hess, inauguration of two new Gauleiters; 9. Gifts presented to wives of soldiers on front; 10. Bavaria, U-Boat Commander Schiffke at a resort; 11. Berlin, U-Boat captain speaks to youth; 12. Great Deutschland Regiment on maneuvers in snow; 13. Sailors on mine sweepers, destroyers, and PT boats leave port; 14. South Italy, German and Italian planes take off to Africa.
    - Reel 546
      Incomplete
      Part 2 only:
      1. Berghof, Hitler meets with Yugoslavian officials; 2. Sonnenhof, Dr. Ley, Hitler Youth leaders; 3. Hitler Youth leaders get training and take classes; 4. Berlin, Goebbels addresses Berlin workers; 5. Berlin, Chief of Danish Police on visit to police memorial; 6. Berlin, German police on "Honor Day of the Police"; 7. U-Boat Captain von Stockhausen arrives in home town with crew for celebration; 8. Germany, workers in Siemens factory of water power generator; 9. Arno Breker works on sculpture; 10. Paris, German pilots on leave ice skating.
    - Reel 547
      1. Munich, Hitler, Hess, and Goering attend funeral of Hermann Kriebel; 2. France, Goering gives Ritter Cross to pilots; 3. Goering and general staff have meeting; 4. Berghof, Hitler and Goering meet; 5. Italy, Mussolini, Franco, Serrano-Sunor meet and review honor guard; 6. Berlin, new Japanese ambassador, General Oshima; 7. West Front, Gen. Yamashita visits German army and navy units; 8. Lithuania, Folk Deutsch leave farms for Germany; 9. Poland, factory workers in factory; 10. Prague, Victor Lutze, von Neurath, review troops and swear in unit called "52."
      11. Berlin, Leni Riefenstahl and other movie stars, Goebbels at Reich film conference; 12. Film actors celebrate People's Film Day; 13. Himmler, Heydrich, police sports festival; 14. Max Schmelling, boxing champion, volunteered for paratroops; 15. Sepp Dietrich reviews and decorates members of SS; 16. Sicily, German general talks to officers on airfield; 17. Tripoli, crew of German plane see town and talk with people; 18. Crew of light cruiser sunbathe and relax on deck; 19. Same crew boards and sinks British ships.
    - Reel 548, 1941
      1. Munich, Feb. 24, 1941, Hitler, Hess, Ley, Gauleiter Wagner, memorial celebration of founding of Nazi party; 2. Berghof, Oshima, von Ribbentrop meet with Hitler; 3. Vienna, March 1, arrives in city for signing of Bulgaria to Axis; 4. Vienna, treaty is signed; 5. Vienna, Hitler gives reception for diplomats; 6. 5th international winter sports week.
      8. Hockey game between Sweden and Germany; 9. Tyrol, army school for mountain guides; 10. Troops and dogs train for messenger work; 11. Bulgaria, German engineers build bridge; 12. Infantry regiment on maneuvers; 13. Coast Guardsmen on patrol in boat.
    - Reel 549
      "Special Report of the German Weekly Newsreel": German troops enter Bulgaria with the civilian population greeting them; regular reels resume.
      1. China, Japanese sailors on gunboats in Yangtze River; 2. Japanese cavalry and infantry taking on Chinese resistance; 3. Spain, many fight large fire in city; 4. Poland, German engineers clear river of ice; 5. Berlin, Adolf Huhnlein decorates members of NSKD Trumpet Corps; 6. Hess, Goebbels, Axmann attend 6th winter sport competition of Hitler Youth; 7. Breslau, Himmler, swearing in of Romanian-Germans as citizens; 8. Leipzig, Goebbels, opening of spring industrial German fair.
      9. Vienna, Goering, Antonescu meet to talk about economics; 10. Linz, Hitler visits workers on bridge being built; 11. School for submarine crews; 12. Submarine shipyard with two U-Boats launched; 13. Bulgaria, crews of Luftwaffe land at new base; 14. Bulgaria, more German troops entering Bulgaria; 15. Brenner Pass, German troops enroute to Africa via train; 16. Troops board transport ship for Africa; 17. General of Luftwaffe visits airbase as planes prepare and take off for bombing run.
    - Reel 550
      1. Tokyo, Matsuokuo, representatives from Thailand and Indo-China arrive for talks; 2. Berlin, fencing competition; 3. Stuttgart, soccer competition; 4. Berlin, ice skating exhibition; 5. Vienna, Goebbels, 3 year celebration of Austria unification with Germany; 6. Lintz, continuation of celebration with surprise visit by Hitler; 7. Berlin, Hitler, Goering, Himmler, memorial day for war heroes parade; 8. Bulgaria, German troops entering towns; 9. Admiral Doenitz decorates returning U-Boat crew and captain; 10. Captain Kretschmer receives return welcome; 11. Crew of cruiser returns from mission with British prisoners; 12. Tripoli, Rommel reviews troops marching through city; 13. Storm Pioneer Troops on maneuvers.
    - Reel 551
      Incomplete reel
      1. China, Japanese troops secure communication lines; 2. München, von Ribbentrop, Hitler meet Hungarian foreign minister at war memorial; 3. Berlin, track athletes at sports festival; 4. Berlin, visitors at exhibition of newspaper war caricatures; 5. SS troops count money collected for Winter Help Fund; 6. Berlin, civilians at Armed Forces Day celebrations; 7. Posen, Hitler Youth at Culture Day; 8. Posen, Goebbels arriving at theater for show; 9. Warsaw, German soldiers repair indoor swimming pool; 10. Norway, civilian workers in railroad tunnel; 11. Norway, inexperienced sailors skiing and falling down; 12. France, Goering meets with his general staff; 13. Bulgaria, German troops cross pass on Balkan mountains; 14. Tripoli, Rommel, German and Italian troops march through city; 15. North Africa, soldiers cover planes in sand storm; 16. German bombers take off for England.
    - Reel 552, 1941
      1. March 30, 1941, Berlin, Hitler Youth and BDM youths initiation of new members; 2. Berlin, March 27th, Matsuoka, Japanese Foreign Minister, visits for official state visit with Hitler and all top Nazi officials, von Ribbentrop, Keitel, Yamashita, Goering. This scene continues for the rest of the reel
      3. Matsuoka continues visit with Hitler and others; 4. Bulgaria, troops work on tanks; 5. King Boris visits Stuka field to review troops and planes; 6. Tripoli, soldiers relax on supply ships and Rommel takes pictures of tanks being unloaded; 7. German troops move toward front line; 8. Shot down spitfire and RAF pilots taken prisoner and interrogated; 9. Weather balloon is launched and planes take off; 10. In Atlantic, multiple scenes of German naval activities across the Atlantic are shown.
    - Reel 553
      1. State funeral for head of Medical Corps; 2. Prague, von Neurath, Rosenberg, 2nd anniversary of establishment of protectorate; 3. Pressburg, Dr. Tisso, celebration for establishment of Slovakian state; 4. Poland, oil drillers and workers; 5. Volks Deutsch from East arrive in Germany; 6. Vienna, German refugees from Yugoslavia arrive via the Danube; 7. War factory, building timer fuses and girls having a snowball fight; 8. 250th anniversary of States Theater; 9. Civilians attend exhibition on theater; 10. Berlin, Goebbels presents "ring of honor" to Emil Jennings; 11. Danzig, Professor Fritz Klimsch, sculpts head and exhibition of his work.
      12. Soldier receives Ritter Cross; 13. Railroad engineers building a bridge and testing it; 14. Bulgaria, King Boris watches German maneuvers; 15. North Africa, supplies delivered via plane to ground forces; 16. Various activities with soldiers in desert; 17. Italian desert corps in sand storm; 18. Germany, Doenitz, U-Boats launched from shipyard; 19. Crew of U-Boat in action; special report.
      Part 3:
      1. April 6, Berlin, Goebbels reads Hitler's proclamation to the people; 2. Ribbentrop reads notes to the press; 3. Infantry advance over Greek border; 4. Serbian prisoners; 5. German troops and tanks advance; 6. Greece, Stukas take off and bomb fortifications; 7. Italian planes bomb storage dumps.
    - Reel 554
      1. Yugoslavia, engineers work on railroad; 2. Large number of Serbian prisoners; 3. Stukas and infantry advance; 4. Bombs dropped on targets; 5. Motorized troops advance; 6. German soldier smokes and smiles at camera; 7. Large numbers of Serbian soldiers surrender to German troops; soldiers advance and take British consulate; 8. Map of Greek front; 9. German artillery shelling front line; 10. Artist from propaganda company sketches war scenes; 11. Stukas bomb fortifications as infantry and tanks advance.
    - Reel 555
      Part 1: [missing content]
    - Reel 556
      1. German cruiser at sea encountering ships; 2. Crew of British freighter leaves ship that is then sunk; 3. North Africa, soldiers load supplies into trucks; 4. General Geisler decorates airmen; 5. General Rommel gets off light plane; 6. Soldiers and tanks advance toward Sallum; 7. German and Italian tanks battle British tanks; 8. British prisoners in sand storm; 9. Motorcycles and tanks advance quickly; 10. Southeast Front, Hitler, von Papen, von Ribbentrop, King Boris all meet in train car; 11. Count Ciano confers with Hitler; 12. Reich head in Hungary meets with Hitler on train; 13. Danube, German troops advance over river into town; 14. Civilians watch troops advancing through town; 15. Sarajevo, Volk Deutsch remove Soviet war memorial and deface it; 16. Map of Greece, more troops advancing into Greece; 17. Map shows area of shelling, SS meet Italian troops; 18. April 23, General List says two Greek armies surrender; 19. Map, troops advancing and engineers repair bridge; 20. Planes attack Greek airfield; 21. Soldiers enter town with people waving white flags; 22. Lamia, Greece, German Panzers enter town; 23. SS troops cross bridge; 24. Stukas bomb ships, soldiers marching into outskirts of Athens, city is seen.
    - Reel 557
      1. Berlin, Sports Palace, top Nazi officers in attendance, Hitler gives speech on commissioning young cadets into army; 2. May 4, Goering, Goebbels, Kietel, Hitler speaks to Reichstag; 3. Hitler on train visited by Gauleiter; 4. Graz, Austria, Hitler greets crowds in city; 5. Gauleiter Kutschera greets party people and crowds; 6. Map of Balkans showing army's victories; 7. Thermopoli, artillery hits city as it falls; 8. Athens, plane flies over Acropolis; 9. Greece, SS and Italian troops meet; 10. Large number of Serbian prisoners; 11. Peleponnese, German troops land and unload supplies; 12. Map shows arrows on Peleponnese; 13. Stukas start out on attack.
      14. Tobruk, old map, troops, tanks, and trucks enter into city showing destruction; 15. Dead enemy soldier and British prisoners; 16. Planes bomb and strafe British tanks; 17. Atlantic Ocean, several heavy cruisers board ship; 18. German U-Boat passes ship; 19. Ships stop British freighter then sink it; 20. Captured crew of another British freighter; 21. Different freighter fired at and sunk; 22. Crew from sunk ship taken aboard.
    - Reel 558
    - Reel 559
      1. Japan, Japanese workers in artillery factory; 2. Toyooka, young Japanese officers being commissioned; 3. Utrecht, parade of local NSB youth; 4. Berlin, Hitler awards Ritter Cross to SS commander; 5. Berlin, Hitler, Croatian minister meet together and talk; 6. Croatia, Stuka squadron invited to feast; 7. Pireaus, German troops unload supplies; 8. 10,000 prisoners in camp; 9. Corinth, von Brauchitsch inspects region and reviews troops; 10. Luftwaffe crews relax by sailing; 11. German soldiers sightsee at ruins of Delphi; 12. Germany, production of JU-88 bombers; 13. PT boat factory; 14. Soldiers on super long range artillery shell Dover; 15. Minesweepers leave port; 16. Boat crew shoots down British plane; 17. Stukas going across Channel.
    - Reel 560
      1. Japanese bombers raid Chinese supply depot; 2. Japanese infantry advance through country; 3. U.S. East Coast, large forest fire; 4-5. Rome, Duce, Victor Emmannuel asking for appointment of king for Croatia; 6. Berlin, armed forces track meet; 7. Soccer game between navy and air force; 8. Berghof, Hitler awarding Luftwaffe Captain Ritter Cross; 9. Hungary, General von Weist visits horse breeding camp; 10. Danube, mine sweepers clearing river; 11. Peleponese, General List inspects troops; 12. Propaganda unit captures British soldiers; 13. Ship passes through strait of Sallum.
      14. Paratroopers enter plane then jump; 15. British prisoners; 16. Possibly wounded German soldier, first such footage; 17. Paratroopers pursue retreating British in captured cars; 18. Large amount of British prisoners with papers taken from officer; 19. North Africa, General Garibaldi visits Afrika Corps and Gen. Rommel; 20. Tobruk, British prisoners take things out of cars; 21. Troops in Panzer roll through ruins; 22. Aerial footage of Sallum; 23. Luftwaffe crew study recon reports and maps; 24. U-Boat and German battleship meet; 25. Crew of ship sinks freighters; 26. Admiral Doenitz receives returning boat; 27. Channel Coast, bombers take off on night bombing of England.
    - Reel 561
      1 Gen. von Kuchler visits propaganda unit; 2. North Africa, Rommel, General Garibaldi meet and confer on maps, inspect troops and equipment; 3. Infantry comes back with British prisoner; 4. Rommel eats in car, soldiers try to sleep in shade; 5. Tobruk, German and Italian tanks roll to meet British tanks; 6. South Atlantic, German cruisers on patrol sink British ships; 7. Plane launched from ship, reports back, ship moves to and sinks British ships; 8. Crew of British ships taken aboard; 9. Map of Crete; 10. Greece, paratroopers get in plane, make jump on Crete, dogfight with British planes.
      11. Transport plane returns over Athens; 12. Greece, transport plane makes crash landing on one wheel; 13. Troops board transport plane, jump out over Crete; 14. Stukas attack British fortifications; 15. Wrecked English planes in field; 16. Mountain troops advance; 17. British prisoners marching; 18. Student greets paratroops; 19. Suda Bay, Crete; 20. Infantry advances against British; 21. More troops and machines advancing.
    - Reel 562
      1. Brenner Pass, Hitler, Mussolini, von Ribbentrop, Ciano, Kietel meet on train for talks; 2. Berghof, Ante Pavelic, Hitler, Goering meet for talks; 3. Luxembourg, Axmann, children are initiated into Hitler Youth; 4. Strasbourg, Victor Lutz gives speech to SA troops; 5. Dunkirk, one year after invasion on battlefield; 6. Channel Coast, big guns shell Dover; 7. German bombers on bombing run over England; 8. Kaval, Bulgaria, Bulgarian cavalry march into town; 9. Greece, workers remove canal blockage; 10. Greece, General Lohr arrives on plane with supplies; 11. Crete, paratroops advance; 12. General talks to officers; 13. Soldiers use captured artillery against British; 14. Planes cover advance with bombs; 15. Infantry advances past British airfield; 16. British transport ship tries to escape.
      17. North Africa, Rommel visits graves; 18. German soldiers visit Bedouin in tents; 19. Shoemaker in desert; 20. Supplies loaded on truck for front; 21. Scene in bakery; 22. Cars leave for front; 23. Shore line of Sallum Bay; 24. Radio man installs new lines; 25. Artillery fires flak at British planes; 26. Tobruk, German pilots enter fighters, bomb British.
    - Reel 563
      1. Bangkok, Thai army parades in celebration; 2. Tokyo, Japanese army parade in honor of Hirohito's birthday; 3. China, Japanese bombers, infantry lands and fights in streets; 4. Rome, Duce, Axmann, demonstration of Italian youth movement; 5. Berghof, Hitler, King Boris meet; 6. Munich, Antonescu reviews troops, lays wreath at memorial; 7. Berlin, Hitler, von Ribbentrop, Antonescu meet for talks; 8. Yugoslavia, engineers reconstruct rail bridge; 9. Crete, Italian troops land on coast; 10. Italians fight way to inland; 11. German troops join fight; 12. British prisoners; 13. Roads with abandoned British cars.
      14. Crete, German infantry enter capital city; 15. Thousands of British prisoners march; 16. North Africa, Rommel, tanks advancing; 17. Sallum, infantry and tanks, new German fortifications; 18. Tobruk, observers issue artillery orders; 19. Germans advancing on British, one German hit; 20. South Atlantic, large German ships start attack; 21. British ship boarded then sunk, show faces of captured; 22. Munitions ship fired at and sunk; 23. 4th ship caught and sunk; 25. 5th and 6th ship sunk at night.
    - Reel 564, 1941
      Reels shows first action on invasion of Russia.
      1. Berlin, soccer championship; 2. Hannover, General Oshima, German-Japanese friendship day; 3. Gen. Oshima given honorary doctorate; 4. Venice, Ciano, Ribbentrop, Pavelic, Croatia joins three-power pact; 5. Berlin, Goebbels, Pavelic, and Hitler meet; 6. North Africa, Rommel decorates General Garibaldi with Iron Cross; 7. Tobruk, soldiers march and Rommel watches artillery; 8. Stukas bomb British ships; 9. British sailors come ashore, Germans help to trucks; 10. Goering and Luftwaffe generals meet for conference; 11. June 22, Goebbels on radio gives Hitler's proclamation for the invasion of Russia; 12 Map of Russian front; 14. Artillery and troops start early morning attack; 15. Troops fighting in street; 16. Two Russian prisoners; 17. Infantry advancing.
      18. German engineers remove charges on bridge; 19. Russian prisoners cross bridge, mismatched uniforms, some with no shoes; 20. Crews load heavy bombs onto plane; 21. Bombs dropped on Russian oilfield and rails.
    - Reel 565
      This reel only has Part 1 on the inventory list. Scenes in this reel were only numbered in the beginning, with the reel describing all manners of military activities on the Russian Front.
      For full description, see Ernest D. Rose papers, Box 1, Book 2.
    - Reel 566
      1. Map of Eastern Front; 2. Observation plane takes photos of Russian troop movements; 3. Planes then bomb Russian troops; 4. Map of Lviv (Lemberg), German troops enter city, civilians carry bodies out of Soviet prison set on fire by retreating Russians, bodies piled outside of building, civilians turn over Jews to Germans, beaten and killed by people of Lviv; 5. German planes bombing Russian positions; 6. Tanks, artillery, infantry advancing; 7. Small groups of Russian soldiers surrender then a large group surrenders as Wehrmacht advances; 8. B-110 attacks Russian airfield and shoots down bomber; 9. Map of Kovna, Kalvria, Vilna, Dunaberg, Riga; 10. Infantry enters Vilna and advances.
      11. Riga, soldiers and tanks move into city, greeted by crowds; 12. Stukas take off and bomb retreating Russian troops; 13. Map of Libau and Ionava, tanks and infantry advance into town, heavy fighting; 14. Infantry advances, groups of Jews pushed into streets from houses; 15. Shaulyai, troops, artillery take out Russian fortification, German soldiers smile at camera; 16. Lepaja, infantry advances; crowds welcome, give flowers and cigarettes to troops; artillery blows up munitions depot; montage of advancing troops.
    - Reel 567
      1. Civilians volunteer for duty on Russian front; 2. Holland, volunteers parading; 3. Spain, civilians in crowds in street demonstration; 4. Verona, Duce, review of troops; 5. Bucharest, demonstration for Romanian troops leaving for front line; 6. Slovakian troops march in review; 7. Hungarian troops on parade; 8. Map of Finnish-Russian border, Salla, soldiers advance; 9. Russian bomber attack, German flak, German fighters follow bombers; 10. German tanks advance past burning forest; 11. German pilots enter Stukas for bombing run on Russian front; 12. Air crew start fighter, pilot gets in and strafes boat; 13. Map of Romanian border, Romanian troops in heavy fighting; 14. Ukraine, German troops enter town, greeted by cheering crowd; 15. Map of Kiev, German troops, tanks advance past abandoned tanks, artillery on Russian position, Soviet soldiers surrender; 16. Map of Bialystok, Minsk, tanks and infantry cross stream; 17. Engineers build bridge, troops cross, stop for relaxing and eating.
      18. Civilians at ruins, tanks advancing; 19. Russian tank advances but is stopped, crew surrenders, German soldiers pursue enemy, Russian tanks examined by Germans; 20. Map of Baltic front, Riga, dead Russians and civilians amid ruins, Jewish old men forced to clean up ruins, hand over Jewish citizens to Germans; 21. Map of Estonia, planes on bombing run and dog fighting; 22. Heavy fighting, troops and tanks advancing, montage of fighting.
    - Reel 568
      1. Paratroops of Crete invasion return home; 2. Belgium, volunteers signing up for service on Eastern Front; 3. Spain, members of Blue Division head to Berlin; 4. Italian troops on train; 5. Map of Ladoga, German tanks, troops and cars advance; 6. Map of Romanian border, bombers on run to Russian railroad; 7. Russian train wreckage; 8. Map of Baltic area, Romanian troops and Slovakian troops advance on Russians; 9. Lviv, bodies of murdered civilians carried by Jews; 10. Waffen SS troops attack a village; 11. Infantry and trucks advance through muddy region; 12. Tanks advance through blockade, wrecked Russian tanks; 13. Map of Minsk, Stukas dive bomb, wrecked tanks; 14. Thousands of Russian prisoners, Jewish soldiers, marched to trains; 15. Showing contrast of slums to nice Soviet government buildings.
      16. Troops, tanks advance beyond Minsk, some street fighting; 17. Cars on road to Smolensk; 18. Luftwaffe fighters attack Russian planes; 19. Oberst Molders lands, meets with friends and air crews; 20. Map of Vitebsk, Ulla, Ostrov, Pleskau, soldiers relax and sleep; 21. Infantry, artillery shells Russian bunkers; 22. Engineers cut barbed wire; 23. Russians surrender out of bunkers; 24. Motorcycles advance, cross bridge; 25. Russians surrender; 26. Cars enter city, infantry fighting; 27. Soldiers enter rafts, cross river; 28. Dead horses, tanks advance; 29. Pskov, observation balloon; 30. Tanks and artillery advance; 31. Prisoners forced from house; 32. Burning town; 33. Soldiers eating, smiling; 34. Tanks advance towards Leningrad; 35. Montage of tanks and infantry advancing.
    - Reel 569